Trinh Gliedt

510-396-6601 | Fremont, California | chuot2008@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github

ABOUT ME

I am a solution seeker who fell in love with coding, and I have an undying curiosity about all things tech. I love tackling complex technical problems and devising elegant, efficient solutions that impact people's everyday lives.

I come from a non-traditional coding background. I have degrees in Environmental Engineering in Vietnam, and then moved to the United States to study Business. I have spent the last 9 years in the accounting world, during which time I honed a meticulous and efficient approach to solving complex problems, as well as customer-facing and collaboration skills.

I'm all about optimizing systems (another skill I developed while accounting!), so when I saw the opportunity at a prior job to eliminate a repetitive process and save the team a bunch of time, I jumped on it! I self-taught programming skills in Excel, and wrote a program that saved our team a ridiculous number of man hours.

This was one of the experiences that helped me discover my passion for coding and start down the path to becoming a software developer. I joined Coding Dojo Bootcamp and have learned 3 full stacks within 14 weeks (Python, MERN and Java). Coding Dojo is a highly collaborative learning environment where I built functional and responsive applications in dynamic, small-team settings.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MERN (Node, React, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose), Python (Django, Bcrypt, SQLite), JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, GitHub, Postman, VSCode, API, Java, Eclipse (Spring Boot, MySQL), AWS (EC2)

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Sunflowers | <u>GitHub</u> | Full stack development

2020

An online clothing shop that makes shopping easier for families

- Designed 12 user friendly HTML templates using Bootstrap, pagination and conditional rendering logic with Jinja
 for customer usage and owner usage, including product browsing, product details, shopping cart checkout,
 inventory upload and accounting view.
- Configured SQLite database models using Django framework, Bcrypt and email RegEx validation to enable saving orders and allow storing users information securely.
- Utilized Django admin tool to allow creation of product categories and uploading of product information and product images.
- Constructed page routing and back-end logic using Python to execute customer shopping functions and owner functions.

AQI Maps | GitHub | Full stack development

2020

A single page application displaying real time Air Quality Index (AQI) on Google Maps

- Retrieved information from 2 application programming interfaces, Google Maps API and World Air Quality Index API (WAPI), overlaid WAPI on maps API using Javascript and Bootstrap in React framework to provide users a clear visualization of air quality index by location.
- Identified user's current location using Google Geolocation API and Google Geocode API to display relevant information to their location upon their consent and to search by address or landmark.
- Architected database with MongoDB and integrated Bcrypt to securely store user data securely.
- Functionalized logic using Javascript in React to filter out relevant data and format information for a clear presentation of AQI values to users.
- Collaborated with project teammates using GitHub branches and git pull, add, commit, push, merge, stash.

A event organization tool that helps connect people with mutual interests

- Designed JSP views using Bootstrap, pagination and conditional rendering logic for events listing, event creation and editing.
- Configured MySQL database models using Spring Boot framework, Bcrypt and Spring Boot validation to enable users to create and edit events and allow storing users information securely.
- Utilized Django admin tool to allow creation of product categories and uploading of product information and product images.
- Implemented seamless chat functionality with Sockets, Thymeleaf and Webjar for intuitive real-time communication.
- Collaborated with project teammates using GitHub branches and git pull, add, commit, push, merge, stash.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Accounting Manager | Pacific Urban Residential | Palo Alto, CA

2017-2020

• Managed 4 senior accountants, consolidated a portfolio of over \$1B, researched and provided guidance to staff on new business, streamlined processes with external contractors, and directly serviced equity partners. Designed and implemented excel macro tool that sped up consolidation process and reduced errors for the extended team.

Senior Accountant | Pacific Urban Residential | Palo Alto, CA

2015-2017

• Fulfilled accounting, budgeting and financial reportings for up to 15 properties of 100 to 500 units each. Voluntarily prepared procedures and process improvement suggestions that uniformed new hire training.

Senior Accountant/Auditor | Allen & Cook, Inc. | San Jose, CA

2013-2015

• Performed accounting and auditing for over 50 clients. Originated a new automated budgeting method that reduced processing time.

Accounting Supervisor | Better Bookkeepers | San Jose, CA

2011-2013

EDUCATION

Coding Dojo | Full-Stack Developer Certificate | Online

2020

• Immersive Full-Stack Training Program in HTML, Python, MERN and Java.

Northwestern Polytechnic University | Master of Business Administration | Fremont, CA

2010

Ho Chi Minh University of Technology | BS in Environmental Engineering | Vietnam

2007